And whoever gets
Okay, it's being recorded
now.
Okay. Remember, anyone who has been before the hearing before has was under oath and you're still under oath according to the attorney.
Come on clock one more minute.
>> Mr. Bernard, can you speak just to make sure that we can hear you? I certainly can.
>> Thank you. Very good. Thank you.
You had to write it down so you remembered it. I just remembered that we do it.
>> I never did it for planning and zoning. I have my trusty flag.
Yep. See
for anybody on zoom.
And we'll forgive you if you don't stand Georgette.
>> Yeah, thank you very much.
Okay, it's 06:00.
I'm gonna call the meeting to order at 06:00.
First order of business is to pledge the allegiance. Here's the flag.
I
pledge allegiance to
the flag United
>> States Of America
and to the republic for which it stands
one nation
under God,
indivisible
with liberty and justice for all.
>> Okay, now there's
an opportunity to present additional evidence that we haven't heard before. Is there anyone who wants to do that?
>> I mean,
think my only question would be I did send over to the BAA some information from a research study that hopefully you all had the chance to read
that kind of talks about the appraisal process and the variances they're seeing whether the appraisal was done pre
sale or post sale.
I found it very enlightening.
Not necessarily that comes into play here,
but I did when we were seeking out appraisers to come and do an appraisal of the property, we're waiting for our appraisal to come in. Unfortunately, they couldn't get done before this meeting.
They were actually kind of surprised at the
fact that there was a belief out there that they would appraise differently, whether it was being done privately or bank.
And so, I think, like I said, I think that research paper was very interesting. Hopefully you all took chance to read it and and look through it. And that at this point in time is the only thing I have.
>> Okay now,
Mr. Bernard,
you are appealing
the value of your property.
And you presented
a certified
appraisal
from Linda Fortin.
Any member have any questions about that?
>> You went and looked at that house, didn't you? Yeah, I went and looked at it.
And
you sent some pictures?
>> I said did. I took pictures and I sent them out. The the basement especially seems to be very damp.
They run multiple dehumidifiers
down there.
I found the structure.
I'm not I'm not into understanding
>> how it's done, but the main room that I came into,
I
was told
by
Mrs. Bernard that it was a schoolhouse
room and
its original
one room construction.
Yep. And then everything starts getting added to it and it open.
I
found it was,
you know,
I'm trying to rambling, I guess is the best word,
depending on where you're going and how you're getting there. It
rambles,
but it was, it was a nice enough house.
Did we actually get an independent appraisal or did you have the bank appraisal?
>> We had. I had the one that I had sent in previously
and then we did have another one. He was not able to get out here until Monday.
And so we asked him to get it as soon as possible, but he said there's likely no way he will get it before, know, in time for this meeting or the twenty four hour pre notice.
So, you know, we will have to see where it comes in at and,
and you know, hopefully the,
you know, the decision here is, you know, close enough to it that we don't have to be concerned about it. Right here.
>> We have the one done in August 2020 by Catherine Heber. Yep. That's all I we have. Right. That's what we have.
Yep. That was the latest one that was done.
>> And I know that traditionally
banks wanna make sure they cover their behind
and
they kind of like little more strict on how things run.
So looking at that number,
it was, I
think it was appropriate for the time.
And I think,
I think the average
in general, the average in off lake areas
in Andover rose like 13%
in 2021.
And so with that understanding,
I'd like to take your appraisal number
and factor 13%
increase.
And I think that would be appropriate
appraisal
approximation.
>> Have any disagreements to that? No, like I said at the the previous meeting, I have no doubt that the value of the property has went up. And I think that you know, I was looking around, I think even the highest number I saw for I think Connecticut, the average number was what 18% I thought I think across the state I found. So somewhere between 13 to 18% I think would be a very valid number.
Okay.
So, who's helping us out.
>> What was the original number four zero five is what the August 2020 was the percentage increase 13%.
>> Make sure I did it. So
you're taking the four zero five from that 2020
>> and adding a 15. Oh, that's the total. Yes. Yeah, we're doing a 13%
uptick
for 2021
from 2020.
That makes sense.
>> And, and we're coming up and Linda
and Robert are coming up with
four fifty seven. Six fifty, right? 650.
Okay.
>> And so,
based
on what I looked at
and
based on this appraisal from 2020 and understanding the market changes and it not being a Lake property, etcetera,
I think, I think that's an appropriate figure.
Okay.
>> So
Linda's doing the
assessment value based on
our agreement on appraisal value.
And Linda, what do you have? That would be 320,355.
That's what I got to.
>> All right. So, I mean, I would like to make a motion that we accept based on
this very complete appraisal report from 2020 with the market
uptick
of 13%
that
locating 70
of that value comes to an assessment of $320,355
and I think that's a fair and accurate value.
So I'd like motion
to accept it.
>> Second.
I'll second it. Okay.
All in favor.
Aye. Aye.
And since the, there is no disagreement,
the chair will
abstain.
Okay.
I'm not disagreeing. I'm just saying I'll abstain.
Okay. Thank you very much. Thank you Have very
a good evening. You too. You too. Thank you.
>> The chair does have the option to abstain if there's no conflict. I just thought I'd. Yeah, that's true. Which I found out from a prior,
>> chairperson. Let's move up.
And we're gonna seat Mr. Hamburger in my place for the next two.
Okay.
Thank you, Alan.
Actually closer.
>> Okay.
No.
This is going to be.
We're doing Daniels next or Alan's next.
We're doing Daniel's next around. We
>> said Alan and then I was gonna be last Georgia. Okay,
thank you. All
>> right. Well, you can come and sit over here.
I said, you're up. So
so come and sit in front of us.
Can we sit right here?
Know, you can sit anywhere you want. Okay.
>> I'm under oh I understand that and all I'm going to do for the board is to
state for the record that I had an independent appraisals done by Connecticut certified
appraiser who lives in Hebron.
And the appraisal was 432,000,
making the assessment $3.00 2 even, 302,000.
And I truly believe
that the four thirty two strongly represents the House because it is a nineteen thirty home
and the septic
is not even on file.
So, it's a detriment. It's working
and so it counts,
but it's going to fail in the near future and it's going to be extremely expensive
to maintain a new system because I have to drill a new well as well. So, I'm saying that
four thirty two is a very fair
appraisal of my property.
>> Alan, I have one question. You said the assessment comes to 302,000
even, it's 302,400.
Someone do the numbers for me. $4.32
times
70%.
Seven is
302,400.
>> Okay, I stand correct. That's the only that's the only challenge I have. Thank you.
Okay.
Want to make a motion before we do the discussion.
>> I'll make a motion that we
assess this property at 302400
or the assessment.
Yes, I said that right.
Second,
I'll second it.
Okay.
Is there any discussion.
>> So,
I did, me being the new guy here,
I
did a bunch of research on this. You know, I watched the
video of the prior hearing back in February to see
the detailed presentation
that Mr. Roy made
and examined
his
analysis of
the land value and his belief of why the land was overvalued because it's a sloping property
and
the average for the lake. I just want to point out that averages can be misleading.
It isn't necessarily
a good way to analyze building properties because
you start out once you have an approved lot with a certain value, whether it's 0.1 acres or 0.4 acres, you know, you're going to start out at $100,000 or $150,000
You're going to go up from there. And averages can be misleading because of that. And also, if somebody has a subdiviteable lot, you know, on a per acre basis, that lot is going to be worth a whole lot more than a non subdiviteable lot. I'm not really saying anything that you don't already know, I think. And you know, if the lot has ledge on it or if it has wetlands and there's a whole bunch of things. So averages can be misleading.
And
also in some of the prior cases that we've heard, and just like the previous one, we really didn't take into account what the assessor, you know, we kind of, we kind of dismissed, quite frankly, what the assessor said,
and merely took the appraisal
as as the gospel, really, you know, without evaluating at all. Now it would certainly help if the town assessor was here so that we could ask him questions about how we arrived at the values that he did, but he hasn't.
And, you
know, frankly, I was I was ready to to try to find some value
in between,
quite frankly, what your appraisal was and what the assessor came up with until you mentioned the bit about the septic system. Okay? I wasn't aware of that. It's not even on file. Yeah, well, it's not on file. You're in the Lake District.
So not only are you going to have to put in something that conforms
to the current health codes,
you're going to have to do all the abatement stuff that has been added. And that's gonna, you know, that's gonna cost you also. So,
you know, considering
that,
I'm pretty good. I'm good with
just got moved,
you know, because the existing value is reduced by that much more having a failing septic system. And
that's, I didn't, maybe I didn't recall it, but I didn't see that anywhere
in anything that we're talking about. So,
you know, like I said, I was looking at on the one hand, the value that the appraisal gives on the other hand, the assessment
and trying to find some calculus for finding a happy medium, but the happy medium I think is down at the bottom because of your failing septic system.
I appreciate the recognition of that. I
>> want you to know my thought processes.
So that's
what I have to say at this point.
Okay. Any more discussion?
>> So just real quick, the motion on the table is to set the assessed value
to $302,400
Correct?
Correct. Okay.
Thank you.
>> Okay. Then all in favor of
the motion
signify by saying aye. Aye.
All opposed.
And I will abstain.
Thank you very much. The motion passes.
Thank you very much. Thank you, Mr. Roy.
And now, Daniel, you're up.
>> Okay, thank you. I
also understand
from the oath I took from the first meeting this is a continuation of still under oath.
And Bob, I think I heard you correctly, you were able to watch previous video, you probably have the analysis I did on my property, which is three thirty two two houses over.
And I also submitted
a certified appraisal and I'll kind of just do the summary when I presented before, which was both Linda and Georgia.
By means of looking at my 82% increase knowing that land values come up agreed was to me a large stretch. Obviously, I want to do my homework on what was going on. What I assembled there is an analysis both around the lake area than the overall town.
And then doing research
on
what the statue is and what a mass
evaluation that the towns do and then how when it goes to court if you fight it, what has to be per the statute fair market value.
The only way that is recognized is what you were just talking about going to get a certified appraiser matter of fact.
I'll add additional information since we last met when I got to go review some of the court cases that were previously brought for town of Andover and some of the comments that are in that document
where it was considered including with the assessor for the town of Andover, that process is an opinion because it's a mass calculation
that they then adjust to.
The only way you can go down per individual house is to get market value.
And when you do an assessment,
the best one to use is market versus cost or income. There's three different types you can do.
And so I knew that even though I wrote that whole report and my opinion on having just recently
built that house and knowing the cost,
that wasn't still going to be the value that what was in the market. So the reason I paid and brought that forth is that's what's recognized. So before I told Georgette and Linda
is that that puts me at a 60%
increase, which is still on the very high end on the late values of increases,
but I have to accept that as the results of what the market value would be.
So what was outstanding the last time we talked was I knew there was a bunch of appraisals coming in as part of the appeal process. They were going to be looked at
making sure there was no gaps to how they were done. I walked through mine. You saw that on the video,
what I mentioned, including like for quality of the house, etc.
The new information when I went back to research
previous cases, what was interesting to me
is the way the system works with a house raid
is there's only four ways to adjust the value of a house coming out of the mass appeal. And John Chaponis mentioned this in the last court case.
The first
option is an assessor can go in and just override the value and say, I think your house is worth X and just put it in. He talked about that that is not probably the way to do it because if you think the house is valued more, you should say the land's valued more,
the grade is greater, etc.
And when you adjust those, they become a multiplying factor to tell you a house, why the value that I was being assessed
currently
was so high.
It also brings to bear why it was an A plus plus.
So when I talked to Vision Government Services part of my hearing and I asked Mimi,
Mackie what
is the grade factor? What is that supposed to be used in your system talking as a company?
What does grades do?
And
it's bared out in the previous court case. It's just a multiplier.
And the comment she made to me is
a town can elect
the amount of grades they want to use for the population
of dwellings and the houses they have and the quality they have to be fair to help adjust for the market.
So what that means on a scale of 10,
C minus C, C plus, B minus B, B plus, A minus A, A plus, A plus plus, that covers the full range.
And the comment was we do not normally see a town like Andover having to use the full range or the high range, but that's their selection.
Well, that offers up is that if you take a house of mine on square footage, you saw my calculation put in, it's gonna flag as overpriced within the system, unless I put a multiplier. And the way you can do the two multipliers for new construction is add land value up and grade up to make that okay.
And that's what was done in this case, my house is adjusted as an A plus plus not because of the building quality checklist,
which is the standard.
But john having a fixed price in wanting to get to that market value what he believes is the cost.
Right wrong and different when he adjusts that and pops that price out,
I look at it and saying I don't need that quality.
That's why I was telling Georgia and Linda last time with the standards I have I'm not superior quality, so it's not really using the checklist.
And so John uses that as a way to try to justify the higher price. The only way I can come in as a homeowner and challenge it is, what is the price? So again, it comes back to the certified person
looking at current market. Georgia, I know you sent me an email saying why didn't I use houses all on the lake in that? Well, as Linda Fortin explained to me, that would actually go in more in my favor and she would be unjust doing that.
She would take my house which is more of a higher end house to the lake and back it down to lower grade ones and the amount of deduction they would have it would have dropped my price. So she kept me high both for the two
properties she chose on Andover Lake and then waterfront property in the surrounding area.
So even though it would have been in my favor to use additional sales around the lake that were lower quality or prices that not be as high, she had by her certification to find what she thought was existing
market value houses.
Meaning houses that were on lakes
that were quality enough that would come more into a price range, and so all the comparables that are on my
appraisal
from Linda all map to that end.
The $7.65
comes in to her for what was being sold for the type of value of my home
to be adjusted to the $7.65.
The other thing that stood out in the in in which was balanced between some of the judge and the court case
is once you get to the point of saying what's market value,
it's more of an exact science to get a certified person to go through all of that process than what's coming out of a mass town appraisals
or assessment.
That is considered opinion.
John Chiponas backed that up during the testimony. It is opinion because it's just a calculation that draws out.
That's where he had a lot of discussion. He then goes around and can make adjustments for all the different properties.
What I thought was the biggest disparity to me,
more of a global,
is the lake seems to have paid the burden of a lot of the output of this being the increase versus the rest of the town.
So if you look at the grade on really nice homes in other areas, the highest I could find was a B plus. Well the reason being you don't have to adjust it for the multiplier because the price of this the house is valued less.
So that that's kind of the whole analysis report Bob just for your benefit was that was my first approach to try to figure out but when it comes down to if you're gonna ask what the statute says it's fair market value and what's accepted if I go to court, Nando were to go to court, they would have to pay for a legal independent
certified
appraisal
similar to what Linda presented.
And the last thing I would say is just understanding
some of the previous meetings that taken place and since there was no pushback,
think there's like six or seven that have been accepted.
So I don't think I would be the outlier if you accept the $7.65
as
the true value of my property at 332 Lake Road.
Again, that's a 60% increase. Think Georgette when you wrote me the email that says that's the price of being on the lake, know the higher end,
and I mentioned yours was an 18%
increase.
Know the difference between
82 to 60 still hard to swallow. I think it's a fair market that I have to accept as a taxpayer. That's the value of my house.
But there is big disparities within the process of what people, you know, had to get as a difference. And so for me, fair the fair value, which I told you last time,
is acceptable of taking Linda's work and saying that's what it is today.
So that's kind of my presentation of the update and I'll leave it for questions.
>> All right, well,
the thing that I did comment was that where you are on that side of the lake
is the preferred side of the lake because the water is deep. On my side, you cannot go swimming.
You can, you have to, you could put a boat in and then go out somewhere where it's deep
and swim that way. It, this side of the lake is a lot different. Some of it, as you go along around
the cove areas, they're swampy, they've all filled in by eutrophication.
So there's various
areas in the lake
that are not as desirable,
but luckily
you and your brother and people on that side have the better part
of Andover Lake. And that's all I was
saying
as And far as
>> that was brought up in some of the previous cases when you read those transcripts and the judge said,
it's the view of the lake in the land that is being assessed,
not the use of the lake. And the lake is actually owned by the lake association,
not the owners so whatever the conditions are is not part of the property owners.
Purview as far as what part of the lake they can use
Meaning people can go to the beach, they can go to get the access through the El Pollo and
and enjoy the lake. But what's the value is a lake view, not a lake use.
>> When you go to sell your property,
if you cannot swim
in front of your house because it's all swamp,
you're not gonna get as much money for your house as if you could just go to the edge of the water and get in the water and swim.
>> Let me let me ask a question here.
This this idea of the quality of the lake that
abuts the house,
is that taken into consideration
in our assessment or in this appraisal? Does does that information
show up in any of these documents? Not that I know of. No, and it's
not relevant to this discussion.
>> Correct, and that's what Bob I was saying, that's what when it was brought up with the previous appraisal by the town in front of the judge in the last time it was fought the same thing the judge said. It's not about the
use of the lake. It's a lake view property that gives it the value for the landowner.
And that's what was considered in Linda's appraisal is what would my house sell for,
>> where it sits, part of the lake, what the house is, etcetera. Right. If there were a dock on the lake, that might have some sway because again, that's utility, that's something that you can see.
Looking at the pictures, you don't have a dock, do you? No.
Okay.
So again, I'm the newcomer to all this, and I took
a long hard look at all of this.
And again, I'm kind of
the quandary here is that on the one hand we have a certified
appraisal from somebody who's been doing this for however many decades,
and on the other side we have
vision services
and
Mr.
Mr. Chiponis who's done this also for decades.
So we have
what should be considered credible values
that disagree with one another,
and really the issue is how do we find out, you know, which one
is more true? How do reconcile
differences between these?
And,
you know,
we'd like to think that a certified appraisal
is, you know,
as the attorneys say, it carries a lot of weight.
But there's an old joke that comes to mind, is that, you know, may your insurance man and your tax man never meet each other.
And what it means is that
you can make an appraisal come out pretty much any way you want, depending on the comparable properties that you choose. There's a lot of subjective
evaluation
in that. If you're trying to get an appraisal for sale, it's not going to come up with the same number as an appraisal
for tax purposes or for insurance purposes.
So I have to take a, you know, I have to look at that and take it with a little bit of grain of salt.
And like I say, you know, Chiponus and Vision don't just pull numbers out of thin air either. And so how do we reconcile
the
$100,000
difference between
these two numbers? You know, you can't
say one is completely correct and the other isn't.
>> Well,
to be clear on that, from the court end,
if I was to go to court and challenge it,
the town would have to pay
for another independent
appraisal certified.
Will not use
that
assessment that Massa and John's input.
That is not considered
an actual value for fair market. It's considered what the courts called an opinion because it's just a mass calculation that's then adjusted.
And when I read the transcript for the last case, which was the Robert Hunt case,
Even John and the testimony agreed to the attorney for the both the town attorney is it is considered opinion because
it's just a large calculation.
It calculates by square foot, it gives you margin for
calculation grades and it just plots it out. What John then is supposed
to do is go around and adjust.
And so my comment in the last meeting
was
even when he came in on January 31 to talk to the board members and said, we know the lake went up 43 with a high of 70.
Well, that is not correct. I know I went up 82%.
And so the number that you're saying is his work
is a mass calculation with adjustments that can't be used in court.
They would have to have a certified appraisal against Linda's certified appraisal and
then they would weigh that difference between what the two come up with. So they can't even use
that other number that you're seeing that the town produces.
It doesn't meet the statue of a fair market value.
An assessor is not equal to an appraiser from licensing
And so that's why the town would be forced to go get an independent
appraisal, not another independent assessor.
>> I was told by the town
attorney that
the in
a court case, the town doesn't always
use
an
independent
appraisal.
I don't know how true that is, but I've that's what he said. Sometimes they do. Sometimes they don't.
Take that for what it's worth. I don't know. I'm just telling
you what I, what he said.
They might rely on the court. Yeah,
>> and all I'm saying, Georgia, for what I read is because they have to use for the statute fair market value.
What
the law allows
is a certified person for that state that knows that area to do the calculation
and that's why it carries weight that unless you find a flaw with it at that moment in time. Other thing Bob, if you look at the town of Andover from the numbers that come out,
they fall short of market value. Most towns when you read go anywhere between 90 to 75% because they don't want to be right up against, they don't want to say Bob's house, Linda's house, George is all exactly where it would sell today.
It actually calculates out with some amount of margin close by throwing in recent sales and doing the calculation.
That's where I was saying my square footage was way out of whack for even if I want to rebuild,
and the only way you can justify in the vision system not to have the algorithm trip or flag
is to put in a multiplier that says well the reason that house is worth so much per square foot it's an A plus plus which I argued it is not and that's the only way I can clear the algorithm to still stay within the bounds of the system.
So I'm on the high end. This is the type of cases to go in front of appeal saying why does it sit as an outlier
and the only way I can prove it is go get a certified
appraisal
not an assessment
of what's the market and then accept it.
>> My
my only thought is
that every single person that's come before so far with a certified appraisal we have gone with that appraisal.
So I, to me, it only seems the fair thing to do, to be fair to everybody who has come before us with an appraisal.
I don't know. I can't single him out from everybody else who's come with. Well, don't know if it's
>> if it's fair, if it's right, or if it's wrong. I know. No, I'm the new guy, like I said.
And frankly, I'm
at a loss really
to weigh
fully in one direction or fully in another direction.
I don't know that
the prior cases that have come before us where you've just said, okay, the assessment is it, I don't know whether that's correct or not. Okay,
so
whether we're being equitable or fair is
I know. Yeah.
>> Well, if someone wants to make a motion, then say I will make a motion to go with
an assessment of $5.35
500,
which I believe is the 70%
of the $7.65.
>> You have a second.
Okay, no second. So the motion doesn't pass.
Wanna find like a figure in between
the two
values
to lower it, but not a whole $100,000.
Well, I guess 75,000.
>> I guess my question is what Linda just pointed out if
the previous comment Georgia that we left is some from the attorney if there's no issues with the actual
appraisals that were conducted
in all of but mine is not being accepted value,
why is that.
What did I not do that the others did to get what fair market value is by a process and agreed to that number, which was higher than I thought what my house was, but I accept it.
I don't understand why it's Well, not
>> it might be because yours was such a large, a large amount,
you know, that My that of a $100,000.
Whereas the others less.
>> But my house my house in one year
went incest 82%
greater.
That's why I'm saying
it's an outlier to the high side.
Find me another A plus plus in the entire town of Andover, I was unable to find one nor was Vision able to find one,
which Bob, but an A plus plus
from Vision is a customized custom house, which they normally find down like on shorelines.
That that is the discrepancy
I'm trying to alert the board to is I'm an outliner because I've been cranked up to make sure that price
fits in but it doesn't. The $7.65
is what fits in by market value
by a paid
appraisal which the others whether the value is higher it's just because of the percentage I'm off.
If a 400,000
house was lower it's going to be a lower amount from the percentage it was off.
>> Okay. I'm seeing e plus plus.
I
don't know why they made it a plus plus I can't explain
that.
We
could try
lowering
the value,
but not the whole 100,000.
All right, I'd like to make a suggestion.
Okay.
>> I'm
not going to be King Solomon and split the bank a year,
but I think I would lean
more towards Mr. Roy's
end than towards the assessor end. I'd go like a sixtyforty
kind of
approach,
which would be the
assessed
market value was $873,400
That's
the appraised amount. The appraised amount.
Yeah, and
Mr. Roy's appraisal was $765,000
Right. A difference of $108,400
I took 40% of that difference.
That's $43,360
So I'm going to propose that we add that 40% difference
to the $7.65.
That gives us 808,360
as
a new market value, so it's higher than
his
paid appraisal, it's lower than,
and it leans, it's more than 50% of the way towards
his end. It leans in his favor. It's not fiftyfifty, it's a sixtyforty.
Okay.
>> You want to make a motion for that? Yeah, well, let me just come up with the
test value based on that. So 808,360
times 0.7
would be
565,852.
The assessed value. Right. 565,008
and 52.
>> Okay. Okay. So I'm gonna make a motion that we reduce
mister Roy's
assessed value
from
what we have on record, which is 611,380
to 565,852.
Okay.
Linda, do Robert, want to
>> what was the first number you chose?
What was the first number?
Where do you I I spoke the motion was to reduce the assessment.
The assessed value from
what value 611.
Is that what he's talking about? Yes,
61138380
to 56565852.
565382852.
Got
it. Sorry.
>> I made that motion and I'll second it.
Okay.
Do we have any further discussion.
>> I
need you to state for the record, Bob that what Linda pointed out.
Reason you're not accepting the value of the appraisal as written as provided like the others that went to the town and the appeals process is what.
If you know all the other appraisals value set market value
I go to court and go in front of a judge and say the town of Andover has kept out all of these except for mine and tried to adjust it? What is your basis?
>> I had nothing to do with those other decisions.
Guess
why they what,
rationale they used.
To me, it looks like they completely disregarded
the assessed value
and just went with the appraised value.
>> Well, I think they followed the statute, which says you have to establish a market value when a mass appraisal by the town is not that.
And the only thing that Court would accept
is a certified appraisal so they accepted certified appraisals because that's what the Statute accepts.
Just want to know why your opinion is
not accepting that if that's what the statue is for fair market value, a certified appraisal,
not a mass assessment.
>> I think
you have to bear in mind that a certified appraisal
is paid for by
you
or whoever.
And
so
there could be a little bias there. I'm not saying there is.
You've got to read Linda's
>> license statement in in the appraisal letter in front of you. I understand I understand all that, but you got to understand that the motion was made to do that and it wasn't seconded.
It didn't get accepted. So
we're trying to find an alternative to give you some relief
without,
you know, jeopardizing anything. But you the first motion wasn't seconded, so it didn't go.
And so I'm trying to find an alternative.
>> And I'm just trying to get that on record to the why. That's all Drew. Well, there
>> isn't it isn't necessarily
a person doesn't necessarily have to tell you why
they're making a certain motion.
The first one didn't pass.
And so we're trying to find an alternative and be fair.
If you're not going to accept anything except all or nothing, there's nothing we can do to please you.
>> But if you No. You can do you can do your vote, but I just have to make a decision whether that's a fair way to be treated compared to the other cases. Well, your house is
>> not your hire. Mister Roy,
I'm withdrawing my motion.
Now what?
We're deadlocked.
Linda, any comments?
>> Which means that the original
appraisal assessment stands,
you're free to take this to court.
>> That means that
you will either accept what the town says or you have to go to court.
Understand.
>> So no adjustment was made unless you wanna
give in and
accept what the board is ready to give you.
Have
you made a decision?
I Oh,
>> Linda, did you have any other further comments? No, no, I was just I looked like you were asking somebody for what to do.
>> No, was asking my wife. She was listening on the conversation. That's what I figured.
>> Yeah. It will also cost you to go to court.
>> Cost the town to you're spending the town's money for the lawyer and the president. When
>> we reduce
all of these assessments, it also costs the town money.
So
it's kind of a wash, but you have to decide
if you'd be willing to accept less than
a 100% or
we deadlock and you go to court.
>> We could reintroduce that motion and we can pass it and you could still go to court.
True.
Okay. Do that then.
Okay. Well, you want to reintroduce the motion, Bob?
Okay.
>> Oh, do you want me to read out the motion that was made previously?
Please. The
>> motion was to reduce the assessed value
from 611,380
to an assessed value of
565,852.
>> Linda, do you want a second again? Yes, I'll second it again.
Okay.
Now
all in favor signify by saying aye.
Aye. And I will abstain.
And
so the motion passes.
And now,
Daniel,
you are free to either accept that or go to court.
Okay.
And thank you for coming to us.
Yep.
>> All right. So I think with that,
our meeting is I'll make I'll make a motion to adjourn.
Do I have a second? I'll second that.
All in favor.
Aye.
Bob, thank you very much for assisting
us with this. Alan and Linda, thank you so much for
carrying on in my absence.
And nice seeing you.
It's nice seeing me here too.
Being away from home was not fun.
So thank you very much and I'll see you all in the fall when we do the motor vehicle. Okay? Okay. Have a good summer. Thank you. You too. Stay safe. Thank you.
Good night.
Bye.
Meeting is adjourned at 06:46.